Man, I thought you're off-duty in five?
They still called you in? Tough luck.
Cap said I could leave my gun and badge
if I'd rather go home
and listen to mama go on and on
about online shopping or whatever.
That's what you get
for choosing the life of a cop.
It just had to fucking rain…
What's your problem? Back it up.
Wanna get shot…
Got a cyberpsycho!
Raise MaxTac now!
Fry his system.
Freak's got military-grade ICE!
So is ours.
Go!
So wacked!
What?! Cut it out, man!
Cycle suspended due to insufficient funds…
Not again…
Tragedy in Westbrook. A corporate convoy
was ambushed by 6th Street…
Jeez, mom…
Morning.
Sleeping on the couch again?
You know you've got a bed.
Just dead after my night shift is all.
You and the washing machine both.
Forget to re-up it?
Yeah…
I'll do it later, 'kay?
Speaking of money, when did you say
you needed that update for class?
It's fine. Got Doc to handle it.
"Handle it"?
Yep, all set.
Don't go cutting corners, Dee.
I'm getting paid tonight,
so you get it properly updated, okay?
It's fine. We don't even have enough
to re-up the washing machine.
I told you I just forgot.
Promise me you'll buy the update.
Okay, okay.
Are you going to school dressed like that?
My uniform's soaked.
A military-grade implant
was found missing from
the body of Lt. Col. James Norris
who was shot dead by MaxTac…
Mom, you're on TV!
Nova!
Not nova, David. A bloodbath.
Go on, off to school.
Fine.
Love you.
Maine?
It's Gloria.
Trauma Team. Clear the way immediately.
Emergency evac underway.
All AVs immediately vacate the airway.
I repeat. Trauma Team…
Good morning, class.
Today's attendance, zero absences.
Martinez, David.
You are not wearing the Academy uniform.
Sorry. It's still at the cleaner's.
Where is your spare?
The spare's there too.
Understood. Please submit
a Uniform Exception form after class.
Now let us begin today's lesson.
I would like to ask all students
to log into the Green Room for meditation.
Counting on ya, Doc…
What's going on?
It's Martinez.
It's a virus!
I'm so sorry
for the inconvenience he's caused.
I wouldn't say this is just
a matter of money, Mrs. Martinez.
Although it was
quite an expense to restore the system.
Of course, and I will pay for the repairs.
What?
As I understand it,
David modified his headset
with back-alley software
to avoid paying for the licensed update.
With all due respect, could this be
related to some financial difficulties?
It's no problem, really. We can afford it.
I believe this is a good opportunity
to reconsider David's situation.
What situation?
Well, David doesn't fit in
with his classmates.
A change in environment could benefit--
No! He has to stay here.
He deserves this education
as much as every other kid here…
Didn't I tell you to get the upgrade?
Doc's fault, he gave me a busted drive…
You tried to outsmart the system and now
we owe ten times the original cost.
Sorry…
If you're gonna apologize anyway,
don't do it in the first place.
You said you didn't have the eddies
first time I asked…
Because it wasn't payday yet!
Of course we don't got cash
just lying around!
And can't you sit still?
Y'know, I've been thinking lately…
About?
Maybe I drop out…
Find work now or whatever.
Do you hear yourself?!
C'mon, seriously.
You know we can't afford those repairs.
Plus, you got no clue
how much I stick out.
Anyone who's not a true-blue corpo
gets shit on constantly.
They'll never accept me,
even if I do graduate.
Don't wanna be a corpo anyway.
Then what've I been busting my ass for?
Everything I do is for you, Dee…
Don't you see that?
You're breaking my heart.
Mom…?
My baby boy… So smart and so talented.
I just wanna give you a fighting chance
in this city, a good education…
That's why I put in the hours,
why I'm never home!
I'm sorry.
Shouldn't have brought it up.
Don't cry, mom…
You think I don't know how they treat you?
You think I don't get treated
the same way?
But that's why you gotta prove 'em wrong.
I want you to work hard, rise up,
and get to the top floor of Arasaka Tower!
I know you got it in you, Dee.
Easier said than… done…
Fuck 'em up!
Don't let 'em get away!
Fuck! Suit's limo's plated!
The hunt's on, beastbros!
No one fucks with the Animals!
Mom! Brake hard!
Mom!
Mom?
Trauma Team? Thank God…
Not a client.
Neither is she.
Wait!
Secure the policy holder.
Leave these guys to the city meat wagons.
-Copy that.
-What?!
What the hell? Hey! Wait!
Shit!
You're just gonna leave us here?!
Mom!
Wake up!
Fucking piece of…
Mom! Damn it, get off me!
Get the fuck off! Damn it!
Shit, shit, shit!
Shit!
Surgery was a success. She hasn't come to
just yet, but she's stable.
We'll keep her
a few more nights to observe.
Oh… Can't I see her?
No can do, kid.
Visitation's not part of your package.
R-Right…
Anyway, here's some paperwork and
your bill. Brought your mom's things, too.
Zip us those eddies within three days.
Uh…
There's a reason everyone
in Night City wants insurance, kid.
Have a good one.
Yeah, yeah, looking for
a buyer for a hoops chip…
You gotta be low-balling me,
That's all? What?
Nah, forget it, choom.
Damn it!
What the fuck?!
There's another account…
Never knew she saved so much…
So, this settles the medical…
Gotta cover the rent.
Doc? Hey, you get the still I sent?
Listen, don't think I've forgotten about
that shoddy bootleg you gave me…
Ugh. Whatever, man.
This cyberware…
Yeah, looks military-grade, right?
What do you think it could fetch?
Not selling. Just want an estimate.
Nah, fuck that noise,
no way it's that cheap.
C'mon, choom.
Whatever, wasn't selling anyway.
And don't expect me to push
your XBDs at school anymore!
Taking me for a gonk…
A Sandevistan…
No serial.
Military-grade, this thing, really?
Definitely ain't legal, but…
Whoa! The hell are these specs?!
Drop out of the Academy.
Learn to take a hint, David Martinez.
About what?
Our class. You're not welcome.
If this is about yesterday--
Who said anything about yesterday?
You think I give you a hard time
'cause you're poor? No.
In fact, I consider myself charitable.
And it's not your fault
that you were born poor.
There's no rule that says
a street kid can't attend the Academy,
provided they pay tuition, of course.
What cracks my chrome is
something else entirely.
-Know what it is?
-Choom…
I haven't understood
a thing outta your mouth.
That right there!
Drop out. Get gone.
What?
You're a misfit, an anomaly.
Human trash. And nothing can change that.
Rot goes as deep as your bones.
Best you can do
is not spread it to the rest of us.
Did I short-circ?
Thought you didn't care
so long as I paid tuition.
I heard mommy came to see the principal
to beg for forgiveness yesterday.
Caused quite a scene, crying for
her baby boy not to get expelled, right?
Shameless.
Y'know, it's always been a mystery to me…
How could she afford to send you
to Arasaka Academy in the first place?
Care to explain, David Martinez?
What does mommy do
to pay your way through school?
What does any Night City bottom-feeder do
to make a quick eurobuck, huh?
A couple of things come to mind…
Enough of this shit.
Whoa, who said we were done?
Fuck off!
The hell?
Huh? What?
Oh?
Huuuh?
What's that you've got slotted?
Some kind of freeware?
The Strongarms 400 really does
bring out the best in kung-fu chipware.
Seriously? Organic knuckles?
If you wanna try me again,
better pack some chrome.
Or just drop out of school already.
Mr. Martinez? I'm calling in regard to
Gloria Martinez's condition…
She was stable this morning,
but her vitals nosedived out of nowhere.
But you said…
You said the surgery went fine.
Her body was already weak.
She wouldn't have lasted long even if
she wasn't on the discount package.
Looked like she was overworked.
Here are some burial options we offer.
There's a reason everyone wants
a corporate gig in Night City, kid.
Valued customer,
we are sorry for your loss.
We can deliver the body of the deceased
to your home or funeral center.
Would you like to hear
about our payment plans?
Do I have a choice?
Is our budget-friendly
cremation service right for you?
Waive those pesky delivery fees and…
Good day, Mrs. Martinez.
We've received a quote for the repairs
to our damaged system infrastructure.
I've sent you the details as agreed.
Or perhaps you've had time to reflect?
If you can't make the payment on time,
we'll have no choice but to expel David…
If you wish to continue
your utilities contract,
you will need to pay
a penalty of 500 eurodollars
in addition to any past due
amounts and late fees.
If you are unable to make the payment,
your utilities will be shut down…
Trauma Team. Clear the way immediately.
Ding ding, Martinez! Time's up!
Rent's long overdue!
Keep this shit up
and I won't just be changing your lock.
I'll throw your ass out
on the street, hear me?!
The implant I showed you…
You said you'd take it for 10K?
Six now? Choom, no.
Just yesterday you said 10!
You and I both know it's worth way more!
Yeah, I looked into it, and…
Oh yeah? Fine! Fuck you too!
Fuck!
The hell… Who is it?
Oh. David, hey.
That the big, bad Sandy?
There's not a badge or fixer in town
who's not looking for that beauty.
I told ya, you ain't gonna find anyone
sane enough to take it off your hands.
I'm not here to sell.
I want this… fused right here.
It's high time I chromed up.